<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>England's solar pill agains the scurvey. This noble solar pill, cures that inveterate disease the scurvey, with all its symptoms, which are pains in the head, inflamations of the brain, frensies, madness, megrim, convulsions, falling sickness, tremblings and weakness of the limbs, rheumatick and gouty swellings in the joynts, ...</title>
            <author>Fletcher, R. (Richard), fl. 1676-1677.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B23027</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1357A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[27]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[145]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[225]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R232099</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888813</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888813</idno>
            <idno type="VID">196136</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B23027)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 196136)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:2[27], E8:2[144], E8:2[224])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>England's solar pill agains the scurvey. This noble solar pill, cures that inveterate disease the scurvey, with all its symptoms, which are pains in the head, inflamations of the brain, frensies, madness, megrim, convulsions, falling sickness, tremblings and weakness of the limbs, rheumatick and gouty swellings in the joynts, ...</title>
                  <author>Fletcher, R. (Richard), fl. 1676-1677.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for the author at the sun in Gutter-lane near Cheapside, by Tho. James.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1680?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Author and imprint date from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Wing says standardized imprint is "printed for Fletcher, Richard (author) printed by James, Thomas.</note>
                  <note>Item at reel position E8:2[144] appears to be only a slightly variant setting of this document; E8:2[224] is a variant edition in the sense that it has the standardized imprint for this document discussed by Wing,</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Advertising --  Drugs --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Physicians --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Scurvy --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:196136:1"/>
            <head>ENGLAND'S SOLAR PILL AGAINST THE SCURVEY.</head>
            <p>THis Noble <hi>Solar Pill,</hi> Cures that Invete<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate Diſeaſe the <hi>SC<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RVEY,</hi> with all its Symptoms, which are Pains in the Head, Inflamations of the Brain, Fren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies, Madneſs, Megrims, Convulſions, Falling Sickneſs, Tremblings and Weakneſs of the Si<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>news, Wandring and Fixed Pains in the Limbs, Rheumatick and Gouty Swellings in the Joynts, Dropſies, Agues, Feavors, Black and Yellow Jaundice; Obſtructions and Pains of the Sto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mach, Liver, Spleen, Womb and Ureters, Leproſie, Laxative Gripings in the Guts, Coſtive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, Drowſineſs, Want of Reſt, Black Looſe Teeth, Putrid Gums, Pineings and Waſtings of the Fleſh, Drineſs in the Mouth and Throat, Superfluous Moiſture, Weak Rheumatick Eyes, Diſcoloured Skin, Spots, Scurff, Tetters, or Ring-Worms, Puſtles and Bliſters on the Skin, Kings-Evil, Ulcers, Cancers, Cankers, Fiſtu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>la's; nay, the Plague it ſelf is but an high gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duated <hi>Scurvey,</hi> as appeared in our laſt great Plague; for nothing was (then) found effectual for prvention or cure, but pure and high ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alted <hi>Antiſcorbuticks.</hi> So alſo has it been found (by good Experience) that none of the before<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:196136:2"/> Signs (which ſome call Original Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaſes) can be cured (in Scorbutick Bodies) but by Medicines (truly good) againſt the <hi>Scurvey.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Therefore, Courteous Reader, where you find any of the Signs before-mentioned (whether they be violent or moderate) conclude you have the <hi>Scurvey</hi>) more or leſs, according to its manife<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtation. Take 5, 6, or 7 of theſe Noble <hi>Solar An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſcorbutick Pills</hi> every Night; for it is a Potent Purifier of the Body of Man from Center to Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumference; being pleaſant to take, gentle in O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peration, effectual in Curing, and infallibly Safe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>☞ Thoſe that take theſe Pills, may go abroad with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out danger of taking Cold by them, Eat and Drink as at other times.</p>
            <p>It is Prepared and Sold by the <hi>Author,</hi> at his Houſe, the <hi>Sun</hi> in <hi>Gutter-lane</hi> near <hi>Cheap-ſide, Lond.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>By Mr.</hi> J. Sabbarton <hi>at the</hi> Norwich <hi>Coffee-Houſe in</hi> Deans Court <hi>in St.</hi> Martins Le Grand <hi>near</hi> Alderſgate.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mr.</hi> Jonathan Wilkins <hi>Bookſeller, at the</hi> Star <hi>in</hi> Cheapſide <hi>near</hi> Mercers Chappel.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mr.</hi> Davis <hi>Linnen Draper at the</hi> Three Golden Keys <hi>in the</hi> Little Minories.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mr.</hi> Bridge<hi>'s Coffee-Houſe in</hi> Popes-Head-Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley <hi>in</hi> Cornhil.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mr.</hi> Tho. James <hi>Printer and Bookseller at the</hi> Printing-preſs <hi>in</hi> Mincing-lane.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mr.</hi> Kidd <hi>at the</hi> Amſteridam <hi>Coffee-Houſe in</hi> Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tholomew-lane.</p>
            <p>The whole Box, containing 46 Pills, is 3 <hi>s.</hi> the half Box, containing 20 Pills, is 1 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi> each Box Sealed with <hi>Helmont</hi>'s <hi>Head.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for the <hi>Author</hi> at the <hi>Sun</hi> in <hi>Gut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter-lane</hi> near <hi>Cheapſide,</hi> by <hi>Tho. James.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
